MARK WATSON

St Ives, NSW Australia 2075

0448 488 884 | **Email:** mark@watsonised.com

Portfolio: https://get.watsonised.com | GitHub: https://github.com/Mark33Mark

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mark-watsonised/

Summary

Full stack web developer with a property development and capital transactions background. With a deep understanding of electronics and programming using different languages and environments to deliver great user experiences. Past and current projects demonstrate creativity and an outstanding technical capability to develop meaningful applications for everyday use.

Completed a certificate in full stack development at the University of Sydney to further advance his skills in developing responsive and accessible applications.

Highly capable developing in agile teams using git. Effectively delivers from well articulated briefs or high level conceptual requests.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, C, Python, SQL

Applications: GitHub, mySQL, MongooseDB, API

Tools: Express, React, Node, Handlebars, ¡Query, Moment, Inquirer, Bootstrap

Projects

Flickering - An installable, progressive web application (PWA) developed using a MERN stack. The app was created for mood / emotion tracking. Uploaded and hosted on Heroku platform.

Live app: https://flickering.herokuapp.com/

GitHub: https://github.com/Mark33Mark/flickering

Quot3d - mySQL database of quotes that randomly selects a quote for the user. Express and Nodejs used for the server side. Uploaded and hosted on Heroku platform.

Live app: https://quot3d.herokuapp.com/

GitHub: https://github.com/Mark33Mark/quoted

Weather Dashboard - API application that accesses the OpenWeather API for weather in locations around the world selected by the user. Includes a 7 day forecast and makes use of a graphical interface for improved user experience.

Live app: https://sun.watsonised.com/

GitHub: https://github.com/Mark33Mark/weather-dashboard

Lettuce eat - API application that accesses the Spoonacular API for recipes. Concept was around the user typing in the key ingredient and the application generates recipe ideas. Extensive user configuration provided.

Live app: https://eat.watsonised.com/

GitHub: https://github.com/Mark33Mark/recipe-generator

Experience

Watsonised Pty Ltd, Sydney NSW — Developer / Consultant

July 2019 - present

Privately owned company established for development services. The company is in a launch status until a sustainable client base is formed. Services include refactoring existing code, development of JavaScript applications and database development.

Accomplishments: Developer and site administrator for Prospero's online presence. The site was developed using WordPress as the code base. Website: https://prosperocommerce.com

Developed and built an internet of things (IoT) device for measuring room environment conditions including sensors for volatile organic compounds and dust, using Arduino as the processor. Server side was coded to manage the client side data received to store in a mySQL database. Website: https://watsonised.com/esp-data.php

Woolworths Group, Sydney NSW — Regional Development Manager

January 2012 - June 2019

Woolworths Group is the largest retail company in Australia by market capitalisation of approximately A\$45 billion.

Developed and implemented investment strategies for the expansion of the property business in NSW.

Accomplishments: Sought and received board approval to sell approximately 130 properties with a combined value of over \$200M and profit of \$20M over a 2 year period. Completed sale of the properties inside the 2 year period.

Acquired and developed approximately 20 properties for neighbourhood centres anchored by Woolworths' businesses.

Education

Coding Bootcamp Certificate - Full Stack Developer — *University of Sydney*

August 2021 - February 2022, Sydney NSW Australia

Course focused on technical programming skills in: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript ES6+, Node, SQL, Heroku, Mongoose, Express and React.

Bachelor of Building Construction Management — *University of NSW*

Attained 1st class honours for a 5 year degree including completion of a thesis. Selected by the computer science lecturer to tutor the computer science stream of the course. Received the Multiplex prize for achieving the highest marks in the construction subjects over the five year course.